翻譯: Amber 奇跡召喚暖床小天使 桃茲
看一看誰又拿到了媽媽寄去波特蘭
Well, look who got another one of Mom's care packages
的關懷禮包
forwarded from Portland.
校對: 不賣萌斯基
你打算什么時候告訴他們 你并不住在波特蘭
When are you going to tell them that you don't live in Portland?
等她不再對我指手畫腳的時候
When she learns to stop criticizing me,
大概 就是她死后吧
so I guess when she's dead.
后期: UU123
幾年前
A few years back, I was
我打算和我男朋友一起搬去波特蘭
planning to move to Portland with a boyfriend.
壓制: B B
媽媽說我們到那 用不了多久就會分手
Mom said we'd break up as soon as we got there.
她錯了 動身之前我們就分了
Wrong. We broke up before we left.
總之 形勢所迫
Anyway, lemons to lemonade,
我認為最好的辦法就是
I thought the best thing to do was
讓媽媽認為我已經搬到千里之外去了
to let Mom think I'd moved 3,000 miles away.
- 她很怕坐飛機  - Leigh 你知道我愛你
- She's a nervous flyer. - Leigh, you know I love you,
但我就是不懂你和Beth的矛盾
but I just don't understand your problem with Beth.
- 她那么友善貼心  - 對你而已
- She's such a sweetheart. - To you.
你嫁給了她最愛的孩子
You're married to her favorite.
在你們的婚禮上 她說
You know, at your wedding she said,
"我一直想要一個女兒"
"I've always wanted a daughter."
不 我發誓她說的是"想要多一個女兒"
No, I could've sworn she said "Another daughter."
在她說我是"她的公主"之后 不過你得到了關懷禮包啊
After she called me her prince. But you got a care package.
這才不是什么關懷禮包 滿滿的都是鄙夷
This isn't a care package. It's a box of criticism...
節食書 我太胖了 面霜 我皺紋多
Diet book, I'm fat. Face cream, I'm wrinkly.
每日一詞日歷 雙重侮辱
Word-a-day calendar, double insult,
我詞匯量少且弄不清日子
I don't know words or what day it is...
這些都送你們了
You guys can have this stuff.
- 我一點也不想要  - 餅干我要了
- I don't want any of it. - I'm taking the cookies!
是帶軟糖的餅干嗎
Are those the ones with the fudge?
等她來過感恩節的時候
Well, maybe she'll bring you
也許會給你帶些別的東西
some more when she's here for Thanksgiving.
他們要來這里過感恩節 不一直是你們過去嗎
They're coming here for Thanksgiving? You guys always go there!
- 如果我撞見他們了怎么辦  - 我有一個瘋狂的想法
- What if I run into them? - Here's a crazy notion...
就像正常人那樣和他們說說話怎么樣
speak to them like a normal person.
也許我可以馬上買張到巴巴多斯的機票
Or maybe I could get a last-minute ticket to Barbados.
拉丁美洲某國
- 我下個建議就是這個了  - 嗨 各位
- That was my next suggestion. - Hey, guys.
其實沒什么大不了的事
It's not a thing or anything,
但是我看見Graham得到了些餅干
but I saw that Graham got some cookies...
只是有一點點好奇
I was just curious as to, like...
- 為什么  - 因為他還小 而你已經19歲了
- why. - Because he's a kid and you're 19.
沒事 好吧 我理解
Totally cool. Yeah, I understand.
爸爸叫你分給我一塊
Dad said I could have one!
為啥我們不能騙他咱搬去了波特蘭
Why can't we tell him we moved to Portland?
又 見 彩 虹
第一季  第十集
電波誠譯
這真是史上最爛感恩節了
This is the worst Thanksgiving ever.
現在才9點半 還沒開始呢
It's 9:30. It hasn't even started yet.
我難得喜歡一個節日
It's the one holiday that I love,
你們就非得毀了它是吧
and you guys are changing everything.
你什么時候喜歡去爺爺奶奶家了
Since when do you like going to Grandma and Grandpa's?
忘了你一路的抱怨了嗎
You complain the whole way down.
我是青少年 我抱怨一件事
I'm a teenager. I complain about stuff.
并不表示我不喜歡 你們倆真過分
It doesn't mean I don't love it. You guys are terrible.
這表示你愛我們 對嗎
So that means you love us, right?
好了 打包完畢
All right. All packed.
今天下午 我就會在亞特蘭大
By this afternoon, I'll be kicking back,
一身輕松地啜飲著雞尾酒了
sipping daiquiris in Atlanta.
時間太趕了 只能買到有經停的機票了
It's a last-minute ticket, guys. It's mostly layovers.
提醒我了 我要帶上你們的護頸枕
Ooh, that reminds me, I'm going to take your neck pillow.
是她的損失 這個感恩節會很棒的
Well, she's missing out. It's gonna be a great Thanksgiving
在你的美味火雞大餐之后
with your amazing turkey, and then afterwards,
我們去中央公園玩玩橄欖球
we'll play a little football in Central Park.
是嗎 今年還要玩橄欖球嗎
Yeah, really? You're gonna play football again this year?
- 為什么不 我喜歡橄欖球啊  - 我知道 可是
- Why not? I love football. - I know you do, it's just...
你爸爸逼得你太緊了
your Dad pushes you too much.
Steve不明白你不比從前了
Steve doesn't get that it's harder for you.
我不知道 我還挺喜歡他這樣的
Well, I don't know. I kind of love that about him.
不格外呵護我
He doesn't treat me with kid gloves.
很好很好 真是太好了
Oh, it's great. It's good.
所以他得到有趣的橄欖球小子
So he gets fun football guy,
我就得到一個事后精疲力盡的家伙
and then I get exhausted guy afterwards.
- 沒那么糟吧  - 你去年吃晚飯的時候睡著了
- It's not so bad. - You fell asleep at dinner last year.
- 火雞有催眠效果嘛  - 你根本都還沒切火雞呢
- Eh, turkey makes you sleepy. - You hadn't carved it yet.
我當時低著頭 表達感恩之心
I had my head bowed, giving thanks...
- 表了20分鐘  - 嗯哼
- for 20 minutes. - Mm-hmm.
好吧 不玩橄欖球 你肯定希望我
Okay, no football. Anyway, you'll want me awake
感恩節"小活動"時醒著吧
for the post-thanksgiving festivities.
帶著一肚子的肉汁嗎 做夢吧
With a belly full of gravy? Dream on.
我夢著呢
I'm dreaming.
- 爸媽 你們來得這么快  - 火雞節快樂
- Mom, Dad, you've got here quick! - Happy turkey day!
咯咯 咯咯 我的填充物在哪呢
Gobble, gobble, gobble! I want that stuffing!
好吧 爸爸 你抱得太緊了
Okay, okay, Dad. You're squeezing me too tight.
- 我要斷氣了  - 嗨 兩位
- I'm blacking out. - Hi, guys!
嗨 親愛的
Hi, honey!
那個 給我點那個
Some of that, give me some of that.
親愛的 真高興見到你
Oh, honey. So great to see you.
- 我愛你 我愛你們  - 你們可真早
- I love you. I love you. - You guys are early.
- 早了差不多六個小時  - 我們想避開交通高峰期
- Like, six hours early. - Well, we wanted to beat the traffic.
沒錯 避開了高峰期 知道我們還避開了什么嗎 太陽
Yep, we beat the traffic. You know what else we beat? The sun.
我們一上路 發現路上幾乎沒人
Well, you know, we got on the road, there's nobody on the road.
在某個時間段出發的話
You get on the road a certain amount of time,
就不會有很多人
there's nobody...
- Leigh  - 嗨 我剛進門
- Leigh? - Hey, I was just coming in the door...
- 想給你們一個驚喜  - 寶貝 真是大大的驚喜
- to surprise you. - Hi, honey. What a nice surprise.
- 見到你太好了  - 噢
- So great to see you. - Aw!
你看起來真漂亮 我愛你
You look so beautiful. Oh, I love you, I love you.
你從波特蘭一路飛過來的
You flew all the way here from Portland?
沒錯 所以才有這些大包小包
I did, which is why I have all these bags.
就是這樣的
That certainly explains that.
- Leigh 好久不見了  - 你一點都沒變
- Leigh, it's so great to see you. - You haven't changed a bit.
寶貝 你一路經停了多少次
Sweetie, how many layovers did you have?
看起來這么疲憊
Because you look a little tired.
但愿你沒買空中百貨雜志上的東西
I hope you didn't buy anything from that Skymall magazine.
我買過一個石頭
'Cause I bought a rock
用來藏我的鑰匙
from this thing once to hide my keys under.
現在我找不到該死的鑰匙了 Mikey 接住包
Now I can't find my damn keys. Mikey, help me with this bag.
不好意思 親愛的
Excuse me, honey.
- 抱歉  - 跟上啊 Mikey
- Sorry. - Try to keep up, Mikey.
Leigh 寶貝 十一月來紐約
Leigh, sweetie, this is what you pack
你就帶了這些東西 還比基尼
for New York in November? A bikini?
怎么說呢 我就是樂觀
What can I say? I'm an optimist.
是嗎 在經歷了這么多事之后 你真行
Really? Even after everything? Good for you.
你看看 都皺巴巴的 我來疊好吧
Oh, look at this. Everything's wrinkled. I'll fold it.
- 什么 噓  - 你看她說的
- What? Shh. - Can you believe her?
我看著疲憊 我衣服疊得不好 我不檢點
I look tired, my folding's not good, I'm a slut.
- 她沒這么說啊  - 馬上要了
- She didn't say that! - She will.
我包里有些東西會給人這種感覺
There's some stuff in my bag that paints a picture.
Leigh 你媽媽只是在
Leigh, your Mom is just
- 關心你而已  - 你說得輕松
- trying to be nice. - Easy for you to say.
你沒有被她的幫助激光瞄準
You're not in the crosshairs of her laser beam of help.
如果是我 我會很感激的
Well, if I were, I'd be grateful.
我覺得幫助激光聽著挺不錯的
I think a laser beam of help sounds kind of nice.
好了 我把你的衣服整好了
Okay, I straightened out your clothes.
看起來 你打算在紐約好好享受啊
Looks like you're planning on having a good time in New York.
又來了
And there it is.
對了 媽媽
You know, Mom,
Annie剛才和我說
Annie was just telling me how much she would love
她很希望你幫她準備今晚的晚餐
to have your help making dinner tonight.
- 你是這么說的嗎  - 沒錯 就是這樣
- Weren't you just saying that to me? - Yes! Yes, I was.
不像某些人
Unlike some other people,
我很樂意別人幫我 Beth
I appreciate a little bit of help, Beth.
那我們先好好整整這廚房吧
Let's start by whipping this kitchen into shape.
臟廚房可燒不出好飯菜
You can't cook in a filthy kitchen.
- 臟  - 好好享受吧
- Uh... filthy? - Enjoy.
你在嗎 爸爸 你還記得帶橄欖球呢
You in here, Dad? Oh, you remembered the football.
很好
That's good. Ugh...
還帶了兩個就有點奇怪了
You brought two. That's just weird.
準備好出去打球了嗎
So you ready to get out there and play?
關于這個 爸爸 既然都來這兒了
About that, Dad, we're in the city this year.
為什么不找些別的有趣的事呢
Why don't we find some other fun stuff to do?
什么 去做指甲嗎 還是買女性胸罩
What, like get our nails done, try on some woman bras?
"女性胸罩" 胸罩還有男性的嗎
"Woman bras"? "Bra" Doesn't cover it?
太好了 你把球帶來了
Sweet! You got the pigskin out!
我們還打不打球了
Are we gonna go do this or what?
- 你什么時候喜歡上橄欖球了  - 你開玩笑嗎
- Since when do you like football? - Are you kidding me?
我可愛了
I love this game.
我恨它 每一年都受盡嘲笑
I hate this game. Every year I totally humiliate myself.
不過今年不會了 我發現了一個網站
Not this time. I found a how-to site online,
教你怎么投出一個完美的螺旋球
which taught me how to throw a perfect spiral.
就像 T-bow一樣
Just like... I want to say T-bow.
他是投球的那個嗎
Is he the thrower guy?
Ian 也許你能幫個忙
Ian, maybe you can help. Your Mom is trying to weasel out
你媽媽不想和我一起打球
of playing football with me.
她一天都得在廚房轉悠
Oh, well, she has to cook all day.
- 兒子 他是說我  -  真妙
- He means me, son. - Oh. Good one.
在這大城市 哪里有合適的場地啊
Where's a good place to play in this big city?
很明顯爸爸真的很想玩橄欖球
It was clear Dad really wanted to play football.
所以很難拒絕他的要求
It was gonna be hard to say "No" To him.
中央公園 中央公園不錯
Central Park. Central Park's good.
所以我沒拒絕
so I didn't.
寶貝兒 波特蘭怎樣啊
So, honey, how is Portland?
波特蘭 波特蘭嘛
Portland? Well, Portland...
霧靄沉沉形似"波" 聚起于港勢其"特" 御風而去沖"蘭"破
all the mist from the ports, rolling onto the land.
美得令人窒息
It's... breathtaking.
我從沒去過波特蘭
I've never been to Portland.
你在干什么呢
Ooh. What are you making there?
我找到一份不錯的自制蔓越莓醬的食譜
Oh, I found this amazing recipe for homemade cranberry sauce.
里面用了丁香來開胃
It uses cloves for a savory note.
聽起來挺有意思的
Well, that sounds interesting.
- 當然  - 只是
- Yeah. - It's just that...
火雞已經挺開胃了的
turkey is already savory.
我們有必要在開胃菜上再加開胃菜嗎
And do we really want to put savory on top of savory?
- 要  - 肯定會很棒的
- Yes? - I'm sure it'll be great.
我們還有罐頭備用嗎
Do we have any of the canned stuff as backup?
- 感覺還不錯嗎  - 她的確有些分寸問題
- Having fun yet? - Okay, so she has some boundary issues,
但我還應付的了
but this isn't anything that I can't handle.
Beth 我們不需要備用
Uh, Beth, we don't have need backup
因為我的美味晚餐計劃里
because I planned a delicious meal
用不著蔓越莓醬罐頭
that does not call for canned cranberry sauce.
你說啥 我們一直用的都是蔓越莓醬罐頭啊
What did you just say? We always have canned cranberry sauce.
別擔心 親愛的
Don't worry, sweetie.
你媽要做種新的古怪的蔓越莓醬
Your mother's making a new weird cranberry sauce,
來代替普通美國老百姓都喜歡的那種
instead of the normal American kind everyone loves.
你毀了感恩節
Well, you've ruined Thanksgiving.
我好像已經毀過一次了
I thought I already ruined it.
你毀了我才開始習慣的糟糕版本的感恩節
You've ruined the ruined version I was just getting used to.
波特蘭的手工果醬工廠
Wow. I haven't seen anyone that upset
果醬大罷工之后
since the big jam strike
我還沒見過有人這么生氣
over at the Portland artisanal jam factory.
好了 稍等一下
All right, just a sec.
無名指在二三道線之間
Ring finger between laces two and three...
抱歉 我練習用的球上面有數字
Sorry, the ball I practiced with had numbers on it.
臀 肘 肩 扔
Hips, elbow, shoulder, throw.
- 臀 肘 肩 快速扔  - 哇
- Hips, elbow, shoulder... blitz throw! - Whoa!
輕點撞 我們還在練習
Easy with the cheap hits! We're just rehearsing.
爸 這挺好
Well, Dad, this was great.
沒什么比得上感恩節來場橄欖球
Nothing like a game of football on Thanksgiving.
好吧 我答應過今年我不會玩的
Yes, I promised I wasn't gonna play this year.
我是說過 我們要去
And yes, I said we were gonna go
逛逛紐約 看看裝飾藝術門
on a walking tour of the Art Deco doors of New York,
但是 我們
but you know what, we
不玩的太過的話 還是挺開心的
actually had a good time without overdoing it.
剛剛算是個還可以的小熱身
Well, that was a nice, little warm-up.
現在我們要動真格的了
Now, we're gonna go for the real game.
- 你說啥  - 來真格的
- Say what now? - The real game.
你耳朵不好使了嗎 Linda
Something wrong with your hearing, Linda?
Linda 你邏輯在哪
Linda? That doesn't even make any sense.
我是說 女人跟聽力啥關系
I mean, women don't lose their hea...
總之 這里是紐約 爸爸
Anyway, this is New York, Dad.
主意挺好 但是咱這不興
It's a nice idea, but you don't just go up
在街上抓陌生人打比賽
to strangers and ask them for a pickup game.
- 你們找人呢嗎  - 呃
- You guys are looking for a game? - Um...
對啊 但是你們要小心咯
Yeah. But you better watch your back,
因為這家伙 可是頭野獸
because this guy is an animal!
是的 一頭答應他太太不會玩得太過的野獸
Yeah, an animal who promised his wife he wouldn't overdo it.
我們麻煩大了
We're in so much trouble.
- 感恩節快樂  - 快樂嗎
- Happy Thanksgiving! - Is it?
- 見到你總是這么開心 Eve  - 我媽的晚餐肯定糟透了
- Always a pleasure, Eve. - Mom's dinner is going to suck!
她要自己做蔓越莓醬
She's making real cranberry sauce
而不是去買罐頭
instead of buying the canned kind.
用真的蔓越莓嗎 好惡心啊
With real cranberries? That's disgusting!
那玩意兒長在沼澤里的
Those things grow in a bog.
罐頭形狀那種的才好呢
What you need is the stuff that takes the shape of the can.
從罐頭里慢慢滑出
You know, where it globs out all slow.
發出那種 聲音
And it makes that... sound.
- 罐頭鋼圈才能鎖住風味  - 我就這意思
- The ridges lock in the flavor. - That's what I'm saying.
去拿外衣 我們去買罐頭
Grab your coat. We going can shopping.
喔 太多鹽了吧
Whoa! Oh, that's too much salt.
是少量 不是倒一把
That's a pinch, not a dash.
也許你應該做準備工作
Maybe you should do prep.
好吧 接受Beth的幫助
Okay, so being on the receiving end of Beth's
比想象中的要難
help was a little rougher than I expected.
塑料的刀板啊
Whoa! A plastic cutting board?
你沒聽說過BPA嗎
Have you not heard of BPAs?
BPA 塑料產品中常含 可致癌
- 我去拿我的旅行刀板  - 你還打包了個刀板
- I'll get my travel board. - You pack a cutting board?
我本想堅持我的立場
I tried to stand my ground,
但是我已經有點被Beth洗腦了
but Beth may have gotten in my head a little.
這鍋...要開...
The... the... the pot is boi...
她擊潰了我
Okay, she broke me.
我能攪這個土豆嗎 Beth
Am I allowed to stir the potatoes, Beth?
Beth
Beth?
蔓越莓醬
Cranberry sauce?
感恩節怎么買的到蔓越莓醬
You can't buy cranberry sauce on Thanksgiving.
你們連一個都沒有了嗎
You don't even have one can?
Chuck 我們還有蔓越莓醬嗎
Chuck! Do we have any cranberry sauce?
感恩節怎么買的到蔓越莓醬
You can't buy cranberry sauce on Thanksgiving.
- 我就這么說的  - 你們感恩節不賣
- That's what I said! - If you're not gonna bother selling
感恩節用品 你們今天干嘛還開門
Thanksgiving stuff on Thanksgiving, why are you even open?
因為有人開始采購圣誕節用品了
For people who want to get a jump on their christmas shopping.
你告訴他們我們有很多拐杖糖了嗎
Did you tell them we got plenty of candy canes?
我正要說 聽著 你要是在休息
I was about to! Look, if you're on break,
就好好休息 Chuck 我們有拐杖糖
then take your break, Chuck! We have candy canes.
我們換家好點的店吧
Let's find a better store.
等到最后一刻才想起要買
A lot of judgment coming from the guy
蔓越莓醬的家伙意見還真多
who waited until the last minute to buy cranberry sauce.
開始 一
Hut! One Mississippi.
臀 肘 肩 扔
Hips, elbow, shoulder, throw.
hips, elbow, shoulder, throw!
你要扔到樹也好啊 我們就觸地得分了
If you were throwing to the tree, we'd have a touchdown.
你這手臂跟大炮似的啊
That's quite a cannon you got.
不過你準心還得再加強點
You just gotta work on your aim a bit.
是嗎 也許下次我得瞄準你媽
Oh, yeah? Maybe I gotta work on your Mom's aim.
- 啥  - 抱歉
- What? - Sorry.
我只是 之前沒說過臟話
I just... I've never trash-talked before.
感覺太棒了 就像你媽媽一樣
It's exhilarating. Like your Mom.
抱歉 不說了 我太興奮了
I'm sorry, that's it. I promise. I'm just pumped up. Just...
好啦 布置戰略 你出去五碼
All right, here's the play... you go out 5 yards,
然后轉身接球 我假投
you buttonhook, I'll pump-fake,
你直奔底線 我給你個深傳
you run a fly route to the deep post.
這些都要今天做啊 爸 我累死了
All of this is gonna happen today? Come on, Dad. I'm beat.
別這樣 Mikey 再加把勁
Come on, Mikey. Dig deep.
我們要給孩子做一個怎樣的榜樣啊
What kind of an example are we setting for the boy?
但愿他是在和只母狗跳舞
I hope that's a girl dog he's dancing with.
他們甚至都不是同一物種
Again, with the... they're not even the same species.
來吧 爸 開始吧
Come on, Dad, let's do this.
好 好 好
Okay, okay, okay.
好 好
Okay, okay.
我能叫你兒子嗎
Mind if I call you stepson?
因為我要和你媽結婚了
'Cause I'm about to marry your mother.
沒錯 我們彼此相愛
That's right, we've fallen in love.
始于肉體 現在感情日益加深
It started out physical, now it's so much more.
我永遠都替代不了你的父親
I'll never replace your Dad,
但不管你有什么問題盡管找我就好
but you can come to me with whatever...
你知道他已經開球了吧
You know he hiked the ball already, right?
- 哦  - 跑 爸 跑
- Oh! - Go, Dad! Go!
跑 跑 跑 耶
Go, go, go, go! Yeah!
我們做到了 爸 你是對的 爸
Yeah, we did it! You were right, Dad! Dad?
我沒事 沒事
I'm okay, I'm okay.
爸 撞胸 哦 天
Hey Dad, chest bump! Oh, gee.
- 好些了嗎 爸  - 我去叫輛救護車
- Feeling better, Dad? - I'm gonna call an ambulance.
不 不用了 我沒事
No, no, no. I'm fine.
只是有點胸痛 偶爾都會這樣的
It's a little chest pain. I get it from time to time.
醫生說了是心絞痛
You know, the Doctor says it's angina.
心絞痛 拜托 你們連這都接受不了
Angina... come on, you guys aren't gonna run with that?
弱爆了
Come on, you guys are weak.
說真的 你確定你沒事吧 爸爸
Seriously, you sure you're okay, Dad?
是 沒事 但是別說出去
Yeah, yeah, but let's keep it between us.
別告訴女人們 我不想她們擔心
Let's not tell the ladies. I don't want them to worry.
Graham Graham 走吧
Graham, Graham! Let's go.
好吧 他瘋了 不叫救護車就算了
All right, he's crazy. If we're not calling an ambulance,
至少別徒步回家吧
we're at least not walking home.
我去叫輛的士 你負責把他塞進車里
I'll call a cab, and you just shove him in.
Ian說的有道理 但我之所以能觸地得分
Ian had a point, but I scored that touchdown
是因為我爸沒有格外呵護我
because my Dad didn't treat me with kid gloves.
我知道他希望我也能這樣對他
And I knew he'd want me to treat him the same way.
他想走回去 就走回去好了
Man wants to walk, let him walk.
好吧 但我能叫輛的士嗎
All right, then, can I take a cab?
你剛不跟我撞胸慶祝那下好像把我傷著了
I think I broke something when you ditched me on the chest bump.
躲著老媽么
Hiding out from Mom?
不 不 我只是在收拾垃圾房而已
No, no, I was just straightening up the trash room.
知道垃圾房這樣后我就放不下心
I just can't relax until I know the trash room...
- 她知道我在這里嗎  - 親愛的 她擊潰了你
- Does she know that I'm down here? - Oh, sweetie, she broke you.
這里現在是我家了
This is my home now.
我只是受不了了
I just couldn't handle it.
Mike把我一個人扔在這里 去散了有史以來最長的步
Mike left me all alone, went for the longest walk in history.
我的意思是 能有多少扇藝術裝飾門
I mean, how many Art Deco doors can there be?
我多么想說 我早就說過
I was so looking forward to saying,"I told you so,"
但我現在只想給你個擁抱
But now I just want to give you a hug.
在你徹底經歷這些事情以后
After you've taken a thorough shower.
我錯了 Leigh 我現在懂了
I'm so sorry, Leigh. I get it now.
隨便你假裝住在波特蘭多久都可以
You can fake live in Portland for as long as you want to.
我確實喜歡那里
I do love it there.
他們開放了一條高架路給躺式自行車
They're opening an elevated trail for recumbent bicycles...
- 這個模式關不掉了  - 我知道
- I can't... I can't turn it off. - I know.
好了 我們已經晃蕩五間商店了 什么收獲都沒有
Okay, we've been to five stores, and nothing.
我覺得我們可以放棄了
I guess we should just stop.
是的 放棄吧 我們回去了
Yeah, absolutely. Let's go back.
- 我不想放棄  - 我也是
- I don't want to stop. - Me neither.
我知道剛開始只是因為蔓越莓醬
I know it started out as just cranberry sauce,
但我覺得已經演變成一種象征了
but I feel like it's becoming a symbol.
也許作為人類 我們有強烈的需求...
I mean, maybe as a people, we have a greater need for...
- 找到了  - 我勒個去 在這呢
- Found some. - I'll be damned. There she is.
我們這樣不好吧 這樣好嗎
We couldn't. Could we?
這絕對沒問題 我們用這堆罐頭換一罐
This is totally okay. We put all these cans in, take one out,
- 道德上我們還是一清二白的  - 我同意
- we're morally in the clear. - I agree.
- 我們可以抬頭挺胸  - 是的
- We can hold our heads high. - Yeah.
不過還是別讓別人看見
You just make sure no one else sees us.
不好意思 你們在干什么
Excuse me. What are you doing?
沒什么的 我們先捐了一堆罐頭
It's fine. We put a bunch of other cans in here first.
鷹嘴豆罐頭 湯罐頭
Chickpeas, soup...
聽著 這東西基本上就是糖和食用色素的混合體
Listen, this stuff is mostly sugar and food coloring.
你真的希望有困難的人們吃這玩意兒
Do you really want needy people to eat that?
我不知道 這看起來有點奇怪
I don't know. This seems a little strange.
沒事的 神父 我懂的
Oh, all right, padre. I know the dance.
一百美元的捐助可以了結這事嗎
Would a $100 donation make it right?
兩百
200?
- 我們可以捐三百  - 我們
- We'll make it 3. - "We"?
- 你們非常的慷慨  - 是的
- That's very generous. - Yeah.
好吧 但我還要拿走那罐玉米
Fine, but I'm gonna take that corn too.
- 好像有股穿堂風  - 我不知道 我沒感覺到
- Is there a draft in here? - I-I don't know. I don't feel one.
你身上穿著這么件冬大衣當然暖著了
Well, you're probably kept warm by that extra winter coat.
- 嘿 好香啊  - 終于回來了 你們出去很長時間了
- Hey, smells good. - Finally. That was a long walk.
是的 我們出去的時候覺得
Yeah, while we were out, we just thought
我們應該順便看下新藝術派門
we'd check out some Art Nouveau doors too.
好了 我們正準備開動了
Well, we're just about to eat.
Mikey 你和Ian可以把桌子挪到客廳去嗎
Mikey, can you and Ian move the table into the living room?
我覺得這兒有股穿堂風
I'm feeling a draft.
- 屋里有穿堂風  - 我不知道 Mike
- We have a draft? - I don't know, Mike.
我已經沒法分辨了 這一整天都
I can't even tell anymore. This entire day has been...
- Annie  - 我得過去了
- Annie! - I have to go.
- 我們搬桌子吧  - 當然
- Let's move the table. - Absolutely.
你們不覺得應該先把盤子撤走嗎
Whoa, don't you at least want to take the dishes off first?
我們又不是在法國 我們可是男人
Maybe if we were in France, but we're men.
- 沒錯 - 法國也有男人
- Yes! - They have men in France, you know.
好了 爺爺 我來吧
Okay, Grandpa, I'm taking over.
放尊重點 我們在抬桌子呢
Hey, show some respect. We're lifting a table,
我們不是在做凱格爾健肌運動 娘炮
we're not doing kegel exercises, muffy.
鍛煉男性盆底肌的運動 在基佬中風靡
又這樣
More of this?
在這個家里當個男女平等主義者真難 挪過去一點
It is so hard to be a feminist in this family. Move over.
- 自己找張桌子搬去  - 各位 你們要把我逼到沙發里了
- Get your own table. - Guys, you're pushing me into the couch.
- Steve 你們在干什么  - 從上面跨過去
- Steve, what are you doing? - Going over the top.
- 爺爺放手  - 我在沙發上了 兩位 我在沙發上了
- Grandpa, let go! - I'm on the sofa, guys. I'm on the sofa.
好了 這下盤子都撤走了
Well, the plates are off the table.
Ian 你什么毛病啊
Ian, what's wrong with you?
我什么毛病 爺爺玩橄欖球的時候都站不穩了
What's wrong with me? Grandpa keeled over playing football,
你還讓他搬桌子
you're trying to make him move a table?
- 站不穩  - 橄欖球
- Keeled over? - Football?
我說"蔓"  你說"越莓"
When I say "Cran," You say "Berry!"
- 蔓  - 哦
- Cran... - Oh.
討厭 Eve 我們練習過的
Damn it, Eve. We rehearsed this.
越莓
Berry.
我們可以用這個肉汁盤乘東西吃
We could all eat out of this gravy boat.
你玩橄欖球已經夠糟了
It's bad enough you played football,
還想瞞著不說
but you tried to keep it a secret.
有些人沒想瞞著 比如Ian
Some of us didn't try very hard... Ian.
提醒我別跟那小子去拉斯維加斯
Remind me not to go to Vegas with that guy.
著名賭城 許多人在那留下"不可說的秘密" 有句俗語叫"what happens in Vegas stays in Vegas"
你知道的 Steve
You know, Steve,
你手術以后應該凡事放緩一些
you're supposed to take it easy after the surgery.
什么 手術 什么手術 什么
What? Surgery? What surgery? What...
- 只是做了個腹腔鏡檢查  - 是 在你心臟里的
- Just a little laparoscopic thing. - Yeah, in your heart.
來吧 你快去躺躺吧
Come on. It's time for you to lie down.
所以即使你父親心臟狀況不好
So you snuck out and played football,
你還是偷溜出去玩了橄欖球
even though your father has a heart condition.
我要辯解一句
In my defense,
玩之前我都不知道他有心臟病
I didn't know about the heart condition until after the football.
好吧 那你是什么時候打算搬
Okay, at which point you decided to move the heaviest
我們家最重的家具的
piece of furniture we own?
親愛的 那個瓷器櫥不賴
That China cabinet's no slouch, honey.
- Mike  - 他是我爸爸
- Mike. - He's my Dad.
他從沒嬌慣過我
He never coddled me.
我想他也不希望我嬌慣他
And I don't think he wants me to coddle him.
我們只是對對方要求高
We just expect the best from each other.
他是個70歲的老人了 Mike
He's a 70-year-old man, Mike.
高期望和忽略現實是有區別的
There's a difference between high expectations and ignoring reality.
泳裝版 我不確定你的心臟起搏器受不受得了
Swimsuit edition? Not sure that's good for your ticker.
鬼靈精
Smartass.
老爸 當我被確診時
You know, Dad, when I was diagnosed,
很多人對待我的態度都不一樣了 但你從沒有
a lot of people treated me differently, but you never did.
我不想看輕你
I didn't wanna underestimate you.
我知道 我很感激
I know, and I appreciate that.
所以在公園 你有突發狀況時
So when you had your, uh, thing in the park,
我想用相同的方式對待你
I wanted to do the same for you.
但事實是
But the truth is,
看輕某人與向現實妥協
there's a difference between underestimating someone
并不是一回事
and coming to terms with reality.
- 我的心絞痛沒什么大不了  - 問題可大了
- My heart twinge was nothing. - No, it was "Not" Nothing,
就像我這個也不是因為喝了太多咖啡的關系
any more than this... is from too much coffee.
帕金森的病因是中樞抑制遞質減少 引起中樞神經興奮
聽著
Look.
你是我的孩子
You're my boy.
我只是很懊惱
And I just hate that...
我們曾經那么擅長打橄欖球
we used to be so good at football.
我知道
I know...
現實是很糟
and it sucks.
但說出來沒有關系的
But it's okay to say that out loud.
還有 值得安慰的是
And hey, we can take solace in the fact that
我們依然比Ian厲害
we're both still better than Ian.
因為他實在是太爛了
'Cause he sucks!
每個家庭都有它自己的戰術手冊
Every family has its own playbook.
有些戰術用了一次又一次
Some plays get run over and over again.
好了 危機解除了
Okay. Crisis averted.
明天我們來整理你的衣柜
Tomorrow we reorganize your closets.
- 哦 媽媽 她不行  - 我不行
- Oh, Mom, she can't. - I can't?
不
No.
- 為什么不行  - 你要載我去機場啊 記得嗎
- Why not? - You're taking me to the airport, remember?
一整天呢 我臨時買了張機票
All day. I bought a last-minute ticket,
所以得從波士頓起飛
so now I have to fly out of Boston.
波士頓 Leigh 說真的
Boston? Leigh, honestly.
我早跟你說過 你得提前幾個月訂
I told you, you have to book months in advance.
- 謝謝  - 你把我寄給你的日歷弄丟了嗎
- Thank you. - Did you lose that calendar I sent you?
上面有每日一詞呢
'Cause there's a word-a-day in there.
我們把我們最喜歡的戰術稱作 傳統
The plays we like the most, we call traditions.
謝了 Harris 這對我來說意義重大
Thanks, Harris. This really means a lot to me.
- 哦 那是什么  - 家庭版蔓越莓醬
- Oh, what's that? - My homemade cranberry sauce.
那些是丁香嗎 聞起來好棒啊
Are those cloves? It smells amazing.
等一下 什么 你認真的
Wait a minute. What? Are you serious?
但最后 你總會遭遇一些新情況
But eventually, you come up against a new situation.
那時就不得不換替補上場了
That's when you're forced to call an audible.
- Henry先生  - 不了 謝謝
- Mr. Henry? - No. No, thanks.
秘訣就是讓你的戰術與時俱進
The trick is to let the playbook change over time.
還有對每一場勝利心懷感恩
That, and be thankful for your wins.
好了 誰想吃火雞
All right. Who wants turkey?
沒事的 我拿穩了
It's okay. I got it.
- 這把刀是鈍了嗎  - 火雞已經死了 Mike
- Is this knife dull? - It's already dead, Mike.
你沒必要再殺它一次
You don't have to kill it again.
電波字幕組 歡迎您的加入
官方網站:www.dbfansub.com
新浪微博:@電波字幕組